

SUMMARY

Software engineer with over 10 years of experience in designing and developing enterprise level solutions. Effectively works with minimal supervision, and collaboratively with a team. Continuing to look for opportunities to expand my experience in designing cloud-based solutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2014 – present

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER VII

Alchemy Systems

- Setup Microsoft Visual Studio Online.
- Setup Microsoft Team Foundation Build Server to allow for Continuous Integration.
- Setup common libraries to allow for modular develop that can be reused in multiply solutions by implementing nuget packages hosted in Azure.
- Developing a new solution that will allow proprietary serial communication
 to be hosted using a windows service along with RabbitMQ. This change
 will make it possible to scale the serial communication to multiple mobile
 platforms. Another benefit of this change is that it will allow the QA team to
 automate load testing which in the past has been done manually by the
 team.
- Developing a new Xamarin forms solution to replace our existing iOS and Windows Store applications. This change will allow for greater code reusability and makes it possible to implement new features simultaneously for multiply mobile platforms.
- Mentor and coach the .NET developers on how to implement various design patterns like dependency injection (DI).
- Developed a new JavaScript solution using React that will allow us to play our custom course content on any device.
- Developed a node web service that is used to convert our existing XML format to JSON for our new HTML course player.

2013 - 2014

SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Assurant Field Assets Services

- Setup and maintain Microsoft Team Foundation Server 2012 environment.
- Modified Team Foundation Server Build Definition to use Octopus Deploy web services to streamline software deployment.
- Establish standards for Microsoft SQL Server Integration Services packages being developed by contractors.
- Mentor and coach report writers on ETL design patterns.
- Developing a new order management solution focused around NServiceBus messaging architecture to help improve data consistency while still maintaining a loosely coupled design pattern.
- Developed an abstract logging class that allows developers to write event messages to a centralized database. This change was accomplished by using log4net and an AOP (Aspect Oriented Programming) package called PostSharp. This change has significantly reduced the amount of time needed to diagnose problems.

SKILLS

Platforms

Xamarin

Xcode

Visual Studio

Visual Studio Codes

Languages

C#

TSQL

CSS

Javascript

React

LiteDB

Swift

Database Management Systems

Microsoft SQL Server Oracle MySQL

Certifications

AWS Cloud Practitioner

INTERESTS

Mobile Development Cloud Development Skateboarding 2 | Page Thon Becker

2005 – 2013 SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Microchip Technology

Designed and implemented a Kimball based Business Intelligence solution using frequent real-time data model
to satisfy manufacturing reporting needs. This change allowed for the data to be moved from a macro enabled
Excel sheet to a dynamic reporting environment that made it possible for the site to reduce cycle time and
material cost.

- Designed and implemented a replacement manufacturing certification application using SOA design
 methodologies. To handle the applications complex state model I picked Microsoft WCF Persistence Workflow
 template. This changed improved data accuracy and allowed the team to automate complex matrix reports
 used for external customer audits.
- Designed and implemented a custom ASP.NET application for tracking manufacturing scrap causes and
 resolution. This application interfaces with several complex XML SOAP web services to communicate with our
 corporate parts tracking application. This change helped reduce material scrap by reducing the amount of time
 needed to identify root cause.
- Designed and implemented a custom .NET application that automates the monitoring of alarms and parametric
 data for 500 vacuum pumps. This application required interfacing with devices using serial communication
 protocols. The captured data is analyzed and the results are sent to several third party web services. This
 change reduced the potential to scrap manufacturing material and allowed the team to manage the pumps with
 fewer resources.
- Setup and implemented Web-Deploy on all IIS servers to automate deployment and synchronization of setting between all servers.
- Setup continuous build process for development environment using Team Foundation Server 2012 on Windows Azure Cloud.
- Setup and maintain Microsoft Team Foundation 2010 and 2012 servers.
- Setup and maintain Microsoft SharePoint 2010 servers.
- Setup and maintain high availability Microsoft SQL 2008 R2 server.
- Mentor and coach all new Software Engineers for our department.

EDUCATION

2006 - 2011 Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

University of Phoenix